{"movie_classification": "剧情;动作;科幻;灾难", "movie_name": "雪国列车 설국열차", "movie_keyword": "疯狂", "comment_title": "40 Trivia of Snowpiercer (SPOILERS ALERT!!!)", "comment_detail": ["1.The charcoal drawings in the movies are drawn by Jean Marc Rochett; the artist of the original graphic novel; ‘Le Transperceneige’", "　　电影中出现的炭笔画都出自Jean Marc Rochett之手，丫是Snowpiercer原著漫画的作者之一。", "　　2.Mason was supposed to be a male character; but went through a gender change as Tilda Swinton was casted for the role.", "　　Mason原本应是男性角色，但Tilda Swinton进入卡司后老奉决定改变角色性别。", "　　3.Jake Gyllenhaal and Dust Hoffman couldn’t make into the movie due to their scheduling issues. They could have played Curtis and Wilford.", "　　Jake Gyllenhaal和Dustin Hoffman因为档期缘故没法儿参与这部电影的摄制。他们是原定的Curtis和Wilford的人选。", "　　4.The last one to be casted was the role of Wilford. it was Park Chan-Wook who suggested Ed Harris for the role.", "　　最后一个选角的角色就是Wilford。是老朴客建议选择Ed Harris来演本角色的。", "　　5.Wilford is bisexual.", "　　Wilford是双性恋。", "　　6.They built a 500m set-train for the movie.", "　　他们为电影搭建了500米长的列车布景。", "　　7.Franco elder and Franco the younger could be brothers; or lovers.", "　　大小Franco可能是兄弟，也可能是恋人。", "　　8.Tilda wanted to have a 1:1 scene with Song Kang-Ho; but it didn’t happen.", "　　Tilda女神想和大饼脸来一场一对一的戏，但事与愿违。", "　　9.Chris Evans personally contacted director Bong for the role.", "　　美队亲自为Curtis这个角色联络小奉。", "　　10.Tilda was considering a retirement; but changed her mind after shooting Snowpiercer.", "　　Tilda原本打算从演员的职业中退休，但摄制完《雪国列车》之后改变了主意。（这个……好像和Tilda嘴里的原话有点小出入呢……）", "　　11.All the torches were real.", "　　电影里的火把都是真的。", "　　12.Tilda uses yorkshire accent for the role; like margaret thatcher.", "　　Tilda用的是Yorkshire的口音，恶搞撒切尔。", "　　13.The name ‘Edgar’ is inspired by the director Edgar Wright.", "　　“Edgar”这个名字是从导演Edgar Wright（《僵尸肖恩》）的名字而来。", "　　14.Octavia Spencer didn’t breathe at all while acting her character’s death.", "　　Octavia Spencer在角色死亡的那场戏里真的一直摒住了呼吸。", "　　15.The name ‘Yona’ is from the Bible.", "　　“Yona”这个名字来自圣经。", "　　16.The train-babies like Yona developed animalistic hearing skills; living in the train.", "　　像Yona这样的Train Baby从小生活在火车中，发展了动物性的听觉能力。", "　　17.Yona is the daughter of the leading woman of ‘the frozen seven’.", "　　Yona是“冰原七壮士”中的领队（那个爱斯基摩女人）的女儿。（就是说，Yona是爱斯基摩小孩，其实是宋康昊的养女……）", "　　18.Bong wanted to put groups of children under the floor for the climax scene but the budget didn’t allow it.", "　　小奉想在高潮戏中往地板下面放更多的小孩子，但预算不允许。（好吧。。）", "　　19.The thing that Nam saw through the window could be a bird; or a polar bear.", "　　饼脸透过窗户看到的，或许是一只鸟，也或许是一只北极熊。", "　　20.There was a narration done by grown-up Timmy but it was cut.", "　　原本有一个成年Timmy的独白，但是被剪掉了。", "　　21.Mason is from the tail or the middle section. she worked as a cleaner and got noticed by Wilford. that’s how she made it to the front section.", "　　Mason原本来自尾部或中间的车厢。她原本是个清扫阿姨，后来被Wilford发现并得到赏识。由此挺进了列车前部。", "　　22.Jamie Bell enjoyed playing with Mason’s prop boobs.", "　　Jamie Bell很喜欢玩弄Mason的波波道具。", "　　23.Chris Evans asked to be left alone in the train for 4 hours to get into a right emotion for his monologue.", "　　美队用四个小时独自处在火车里为他经典的独白找感觉。", "　　24.Jamie Bell says Chris Evans was practicing his monologue for hours in his hotel room; looking at the mirror.", "　　Jaime Bell说美队每天花好几个小时在旅店里照着镜子努力地联系对白。", "　　25.Gillam and Grey is in a gay relationship; according to Bong’s imagination.", "　　根据小奉的YY，Gilliam和Grey是一对同性恋人。", "　　26.The martial director Julian Spencer referenced his famous sauna scene from ‘Eastern Promise’.", "　　武指Julian Spencer在电影里致敬了他之前在《东方的承诺》中设计的桑拿间戏。", "　　27.Bong wanted the name for the korean character (Namgoong Minsu) to be hard to pronounce.", "　　小奉希望让韩国角色的名字（南宫珉秀）发音困难一些。= =", "　　28.The actress who played Claude is not a professional actress. she’s an art student who didn’t know what kind of movie she was in for; and later was shocked to see Chris Evans in the set.", "　　饰演Claude（黄色女人）的女演员并不是一个专业演员。她是一个艺术学生，而且参演的时候完全不知道自己在拍啥，直到她惊讶地发现美队也在布景里。", "　　29.Rebel Wilson was supposed to play Claude; but there was a scheduling problem.", "　　Rebel Wilson原本应该来饰演Claude，但是档期不赶趟。", "　　30.Mason’s glasses are from Tilda’s twins.", "　　Mason的眼镜来自Tilda的双胞胎孩子。", "　　31.The protein blocks are mixture of seaweed and sugar. Jamie Bell had the hardest time eating them.", "　　蛋白质块是用海带和糖做成的。Jaime Bell觉得很难吃。", "　　32.Chris Evans worried about how ‘silly’ it would look to be slipped on a dead fish during a fight scene. Bong had to explain ‘the beauty of mistakes’", "　　美队觉得在一场打斗戏里踩到死鱼摔倒是一件很傻逼的事（呵呵，他不懂奉俊昊）。而奉俊昊则给他解释，这是一种“失误的美”。", "　　33.The final scene was filmed in Austria.", "　　最后一场戏在奥地利拍摄。", "　　34.Ed Harris struggled with his lines in the first day and got very angry. Bong says he couldn’t stop laughing at Ed Harris losing his shit.", "　　Ed Harris拍摄第一天为对白纠结了很久，变得非常生气。小奉一直笑话他失态。", "　　35.Harvey Weinstein demanded to delete the ‘fish blood scene’ but Bong refused to cut it.", "　　韦恩斯坦要求奉剪掉“鱼血”那场戏，但是奉不从命。", "　　36.Unlike the audience expected; Park Chan-Wook was not involved in the shooting at all as he was busy directing ‘Stoker’.", "　　并非像观众们期待的那样，老朴客根本没参与本片的摄制，他忙着去拍Stoker了。", "　　37.Snowpiercer might be the last movie shot with film camera in Korean movie history.", "　　《雪国列车》很有可能将会是韩国电影史上最后一部用胶卷摄像机拍摄的电影。（但是之前看访谈，小奉说他会一直拍胶片电影……）", "　　38.Bong wanted to build a zoo in the train; but the budget was short.", "　　奉想在火车中搭建一个动物园车厢，但是预算太少没办法搞。（所以北极熊也许是这里来的……）", "　　39.Jamie Bell was afraid to do the stunt; so Bong did the stunt himself to show how safe it was. Jamie Bell couldn’t complain about stunts afterward.", "　　Jamie Bell当时很怕做一个惊险动作，但小奉直接亲自上阵给他做示范，然后Jaime Bell就啥也不能抱怨了。", "　　40.Bong pretended not to understand english when the American producers asked him to cut scenes out. ", "       美国制片人跟奉说要剪掉一些戏的时候，奉假装听不懂英文。"], "movie_roles": "克里斯·埃文斯;杰米·贝尔;宋康昊;蒂尔达·斯文顿;艾德·哈里斯;约翰·赫特;奥克塔维亚·斯宾瑟;艾文·布莱纳;高雅星;艾丽森·皮尔;卢克·帕斯夸尼洛;弗拉德·伊凡诺夫"}
